

DOMINGO GARCIA ROJAS

C/ Muntaner, 61, 1º-2ª 08011 Barcelona España

Phone: 34.639.520.471

Email: domingo.garciarojas@gmail.com
URL: http://www.visualcv.com/domingogarciarojas

TWITTER: @domingogrojas

SUMMARY: A Chemical Engineer like a senior consultancy with more than 9 years private and public sector experience in the environment, quality and energy industries performing a variety of roles such as environment projects, environment evaluations, ISO's (9001, 14001 and 50001) developments, energy projects, studies or auditoria's, environment measurement and modelling, energy market analysis. Proficient in the use of various database, spreadsheet, technical engineering programs and presentation software programs, such as environment simulators, Microsoft tools, etc. Also possess excellent communications skills.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

FREELANCE ENGINEER - Barcelona Spain (2009 - Actually)

Responsibilities and Accomplishments:

• Energy Engineer – consultancy of different companies:

Energy Audit Engineer for Bureau Veritas - ECA- (All Spain).
 ITCL (Tecnologic Institut Castilla León) (Castilla León)

• MATIS Hispania – International. (Barcelona)

• ECLIPSOLAR – (Germany) - (Barcelona)

ALENTA MA (Barcelona)
 AFFINITY GRUP (Spain - France)
 INNOVETEC SYSTEMS SL (Barcelona/ Zaragoza)

Xunta Galicia (Galicia)

• AFFINITY GROUP (France and Spain)

EFICIEN S.A Barcelona Spain - Technical Director (2007 - 2009)

Responsibilities and Accomplishments:

- Energy quality Area Director in development of energy projects.
- Renewable Energy engineer projects (Project and execution)
- TUV Rheiland external energy consultancy
- Electric Inspection Manager of EFICIEN SA (ENAC Qualification) Barcelona

SGS Tecnos S.A, Barcelona, (Spain) (2004 to 2007) Contractor on Environment and Quality Consultancy

Responsibilities and Accomplishments:

- Responsible of Energy Area consultancy.
- Worked in Barcelona, Spain making all kind of environment projects. Analyzing, design and development of environment

- studies in Catalunya.
- Responsible for the maintenance and development of Electrical AT-stations (ENDESA Company) in the environment area, around Catalunya.
- Supported the energy area in the environment department, actualization of news energy technologies, making contact with the different energies companies and preparing the energy activities sessions of the department.
- Responsible of the environment systems (ISO 14001) of the Department and other different companies.

EDUCATION

Polytechnic University of Zaragoza - CIRCE - Spain

European Master in Renewable Energy and Energetic Efficiency (1.050 h)

SGS Tecnos S.A, Barcelona - Spain

Master Superior Technical Inspector in Industrial, Quality and Environment systems (610 h)

SPANISH NATIONAL INSTITUT OF HEALTH AND SAFETY - San Roman School - Madrid - Spain

Master in Prevention Working Risk - Ergonomics and Psycho sociology Industry specialization (650 h)

University of La Laguna, Santa Cruz de Tenerife - Spain

Degree - Superior Chemical Engineer

(Academic titles link: https://mega.co.nz/#F!DA0AkQCT!GTdaACRg8X9qJASnHpK9sQ)

Courses

ENERGY, QUALITY, ENVIROTMENT AND PRL

Auditor in ISO 14001 environment systems. Auditor in ISO 14001 environment systems. Auditor in ISO 9001quality systems. Auditor in ISO 50001 energy systems.

SUSTAINABILITY SELL AND MARKETING

Web design Coaching Internet trade. Legal aspects Corporative Social Responsibility Financial Risk

Accreditations and Certificates

Industrial Inspector of UTVA (Generalitat de Catalunya)
High Tension Electricity Inspector (ENAC – Generalitat de Catalunya)
Organic Components Leak Detection Inspector (ENAC – in process)
Chief Auditor in Quality ISO 9001 (SGS Tecnos SA)
Chief Auditor in environment ISO 14001 (SGS Tecnos SA).
Nuclear Auditor (SGS Tecnos SA)
Accreditation to work in Nuclear Plants (Nuclear Consell Spain)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Proficient and worked experience in the use of database, spreadsheet and presentation programs, such as: Lotus Notes. office packet (word, excel, power point, access, outlook), Visio, Publisher, Project Manager, Windows NT, Windows 95/98, Windows 2000, Windows XP, Photoshop, Corel Draw, Microsoft Publisher, MIRAMON, Auto CAD, Front Page, HTML, Java script, Dreamweaber, Macromedia flash 5.0. Provision II, Pro-engineer, EES, Presto, TCQ 2000.
- Proficient in English, Catalan and Italian languages.
- Solar technology teacher in different professionals' schools.
- Driving license and travel disposition.

SOME CUSTOMER (CONSULTANCE vs ENGINEER PROJECTS)

PRIVATE COMPANIES

ASCO I (NUCLEAR PLANT)ALSTOM (WIND and HYDRO)

SEATRENAULTGAS NATURALPHILIPS IBERICA, S.A

- GRUPO LAR

- ABB - NISSAN

- DELPHI SYSTEMS

LACAMBRA LA FARGA
TRELLEBORG
ENAGAS
SAINT GOBAIN

- CIDE - BAYER HOSPITAL GALDAKANO

GRUPO HEFAMECARREFURAGIP IBERICA.

- TPS (Tarragona Port

Services)

- ENTREPINARES - PRONOVIAS

- UBISA

- Hotel INCOSOL - ARMACELL - PANRICO

SECOMSA SL (Reus)ASHLAN GROUPARPIDECALASEME

PUBLIC INSTITUTIONS

ICAENAENA

GENERALITAT DE CATALUNYA

INEGA

- CATALAN FOREST TECHNOLOGY CENTER

> Barcelona, March 19, 2014 Signed.- **Domingo G. Rojas**